Lorenzo Fabbri

Summary

I am a PhD student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal). I work under the supervision of Prof. Martine Vrijheid. My main topic of interest is the use of modern Causal Inference methods to answer questions in the broad field of Environmental Neuroepidemiology. I am also profoundly interested in Open Science and Reproducible Research.

I received my Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and my Master's degree in Quantitative and Computational Biology.

My personal webpage is here. You can also find me on Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.

Working Experience

PhD Student

Barcelona Institute for Global Health (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

Student Research Assistant Fellowship

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2017 - 2017

Funding

Meritatamente	2022

Società Unione Mutuo Soccorso (San Marino, SM)	2022
Erasmus+ Traineeship Programme Scholarship University of Trento (Trento, IT)	2019
Faculty of Informatics Scholarship Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)	2016
Erasmus Traineeship Programme Scholarship University of Parma (Parma, IT)	2015

Honors and Awards

Outstanding Abstract by a Student

International Society for Environmental Epidemiology

2022

Publications

- 1. Fabbri L, Garlantézec R, Audouze K, et al. Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic profiles: A panel study. Environment International. Published online February 26, 2023:107856. doi:10.1016/j.envint.2023.107856
- 2. Thiel C, Cordes H, Fabbri L, et al. A Comparative Analysis of Drug-Induced Hepatotoxicity in Clinically Relevant Situations. PLOS Computational Biology. 2017;13(2):e1005280. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005280

Conference Presentations

Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic profiles: a panel study

	SKILLS
Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic markers in a population-based child cohort	
maners in a population susce cana constr	2022
ABCPy for PASC	2021
	2021
Childhood exposure to non-persistent endocrine disrupting chemicals and multi-omic markers in a population-based child cohort	
	2021
Education	
PhD Programme in Biomedicine Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona, ES)	2021 - Present
M.Sc. in Quantitative and Computational Biology Università degli Studi di Trento (Trento, IT)	2017 - 2019

Continuing Education

B.Sc. in Biotechnology

University of Parma (Parma, IT)

M.Sc. Student in Computational Science Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

Service

Students and New Researchers Network	
International Society for Environmental Epidemiology	2022 - 2023
Early Career Scientist Working Group	
COnsortium of METabolomics Studies	2022 - 2022

2016 - 2017

2012 - 2016

Skills